# Kristijan Perusko

## software engineer

#### **Contact**

kristijan.perusko@yahoo.com

#### Links

Linkedin:// kperusko Github:// kperusko Bitbucket:// kperusko

#### Languages

English, Croatian

#### **Programming**

PHP, JavaScript CSS & HTML

Some experience: Java, Python C# (Silverlight), VB.Net Scala, Racket, Octave

### Db

MongoDB, MySQL

#### Os

Ubuntu, Debian Fedora, CentOS Windows

#### Other

Git, Mercurial, SVN Apache2, RabbitMQ AWS, S3, Heroku

## **Summary**

I'm interested in databases and functional programming. I'm passionate about learning and solving hard problems. I worked as a full stack and back-end software engineer, but I prefer working with algorithms, databases, implementing APIs and doing system-wide optimizations.

## **Experience**

2008-2014 **Novatec** 

Team leader | Software engineer

Worked on in-house projects for two years as a software engineer. Became a team leader to build a booking system and multiple customer facing sites. My last role was being a project/team leader where I gathered requirements from the clients, mentored junior engineers, planned and implemented critical features. My other responsibilities included administration and optimization of MongoDB and MySQL DBs and Ubuntu/Debian servers.

2007-2008 **Tempo** 

IT administrator

Principal responsibility in several areas including Windows administration and user support, configuration and management of infrastructure and equipment in 8 remote offices. Managed system upgrade for compliance with EU customs legislation.

2005-2007 Vlado elektronika

Sofware and electrical QA engineer

Created hardware testbed and software for computer aided testing of intrusion alarm system. This system automated 90% of the tests and lowered the testing time by 60%.

## **Education**

since 2013	<b>BS of information tehnology</b> Silverlight 5 and MS Sync Framework	Veleuciliste u Rijeci (Rijeka College)
since 2002	Electrical engineering	Mate Blazina High School
	DC servo driver controlled by IR remote	

## **Certifications**

07 2014	<b>M202: MongoDB Advanced Deployment and Operations</b> <i>MongoDB</i>	MongoDB
11 2013	<b>Principles of Reactive Programming</b> École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne	Coursera
10 2013	<b>Machine Learning</b> Stanford University	Coursera
10 2013	Interactive Programming in Python Rice University	Coursera
10 2013	M101JS MongoDB for Node.js Developers  MongoDB	MongoDB
09 2013	<b>Functional Programming Principles in Scala</b> <i>Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne</i>	Coursera
06 2013	Startup Engineering Stanford University	Coursera